Jonathan "JD" Buendia

(818) 930-0121 <u>id.buendia0711@gmail.com</u> <u>Portfolio</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Github</u> Arleta, CA 91331

Technical Skills

JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Mongoose, MongoDB, Node.js, Express.js, SQL, SQLite3, PostgreSQL, Webpack, jQuery, Git, Heroku

Projects

FlavorCheck (JavaScript, React/Redux, Ruby/Rails, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, AWS S3)

Live Site | Github A Full Stack clone of Untappd, where user's post and share reviews from specific burger joints.

- Created a dynamic and true single-page application utilizing React/Redux
- Built modals for creation/deletion of review post and login/signup form to enhance user-experience
- Optimized database query for user followers/following by utilizing SQL and Active Record best practices.
- Incorporated AWS S3 to host all project images in order to reduce page load and improve server performance, ensuring content security with AWS IAM.

Slaw (JavaScript, React/Redux, Express.js, Node.js, HTML5, CSS, MongoDB, AWS S3, Socket.io) <u>Live Site | Github</u> A Health and Fitness Social Media application that allows a user to interact with many different workout communities.

- Acted as Team Lead and led the research on use of external technologies for feature implementations.
- Leveraged Google Maps API and Active.com API to display events happening within a specific search location
- Spearheaded implementation of real-time chat for each channel by incorporating Socket.io
- Learned proper github workflow through branching, avoiding merge conflicts, and having code reviews
- Utilized MongoDB's flexible database to create one-to-many relationships with multiple documents/collections
- Built CRUD actions for channels, events, event checklist, and announcements

Over Grill (JavaScript, HTML5, CSS)

Live Site | Github

A game where a user is given orders and prepares the right burger on the plate.

- Built full game using only vanilla JavaScript utilizing vanilla DOM manipulation
- Interactive website that follows user input through clicks and reacts in real-time.

Professional Experience

SMCI - Software Management Consultants, Inc.

Technical Recruiter October 2017 - July 2020

- Responsible for sourcing, screening, and interviewing IT professionals for contract, contract-to-hire, and full time opportunities for medium to enterprise IT clients around the United States
- Source candidates by making 100+ cold-calls per day, reviewing resumes, networking, and utilizing complex Boolean searches
- Document and maintain all pertinent data in the homegrown Applicant Tracking System (ATS)
- Mentored new recruiters by providing feedback on calls and guidance on proper processes

Anteater Express

Operations Staff/Operator

June 2014 - June 2017

- Promoted to back end support staff guiding 15-20 operators through the logistics
- Coordinator and first contact for complications that operators run into
- Carry a Class B driver's license; trained to transport students safely and operate large capacity vehicles

Education

App Academy July 2020 - November 2020

Immersive software development course with focus on full stack web development.

University of California, Irvine

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology Major with a minor in Health Informatics

September 2013 - June 2017